<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zip on Damyge Ctrl</title>
    <link>https://damygectrl.com/tags/zip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zip on Damyge Ctrl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 23:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damygectrl.com/tags/zip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The .Zip Disaster</title>
      <link>https://damygectrl.com/posts/the-zip-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damygectrl.com/posts/the-zip-disaster/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month, Google&amp;rsquo;s new Top Level Domain (TLD) launched, allowing websites to now host on .zip addresses. Instead of mywebsite.com, it can now be mywebsite.zip. This can be a bit annoying because .zip is now both a TLD and one of the most common file types. But it can also be dangerous. Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example in action: As you can see in this demo, Matt tells his family &amp;ldquo;Check out familyphotos[.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Google&amp;rsquo;s new Top Level Domain (TLD) launched, allowing websites to now host on .zip addresses. Instead of &lt;em&gt;mywebsite.com&lt;/em&gt;, it can now be &lt;em&gt;mywebsite.zip&lt;/em&gt;. This can be a bit annoying because .zip is now both a TLD and one of the most common file types. But it can also be &lt;strong&gt;dangerous&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example in action:
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Demo: Family Photos&#34; src=&#34;https://damygectrl.com/img/google-zip/familyphotos.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As you can see in this demo, Matt tells his family &amp;ldquo;Check out familyphotos[.]zip&amp;rdquo; and the file name is already highlighted. If you did not understand that .zip is also a domain now, you would easily assume that clicking that button would allow you to access that zip file. However, When clicked, a HTTPS request is made to the domain https:\\familyphotos[.]zip and a zip file is downloaded without even opening a web page. This zip file can then contain anything the domain host wants it to (a text file in this case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me break this down in more detail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software that automatically converts the text of links into a clickable hyperlink will now convert any reference to a .zip filename like &amp;ldquo;test.zip&amp;rdquo; into a clickable hyperlink unless programmed specifically not to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scammers and phishers can abuse this to create malicious .zip domains which download malware, enabling untechnical users to click what they think is a zip file (ex: test[.]zip) which downloads a file of the hostile actor&amp;rsquo;s choice instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using this method, malicious actors can now host malware on domains of common filenames like &amp;ldquo;backup.zip&amp;rdquo; and then just wait for unknowing users to click on links pointing to what they thought were zips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we respond to this? There are two big takeaways. First, if you are a network admin, ban the entire .zip TLD from being accessed on your networks. If you are a regular user, do not visit .zip domains given they are now a wild west for hosting malware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you found this post useful, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/dylan-ierley-28a9aa24b/&#34;&gt;please connect with me on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d love to expand my network and see that this resource is helping people.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
